In order to trap him, he must become him.
Face/Off is a action, crime, science fiction film directed by John Woo.
In order to foil a terrorist plot, an FBI agent undergoes facial transplant
surgery and assumes the identity of a criminal mastermind.
The plan turns sour when the criminal wakes up prematurely and seeks revenge.
Sean Archer, played by John Travolta.
Castor Troy, played by Nicolas Cage.
Eve Archer, played by Joan Allen.
Pollux Troy, played by Alessandro Nivola.
Sasha Hassler, played by Gina Gershon.
Jamie Archer, played by Dominique Swain.
Face/Off is a 1997 American science fiction action thriller film directed by
John Woo, from a screenplay by Mike Werb and Michael Colleary.
It stars John Travolta as an FBI agent and Nicolas Cage as a terrorist, who
undergo an experimental surgery to swap their faces and identities.
The film co-stars Joan Allen, Gina Gershon, and Alessandro Nivola in his film debut, and features Dominique
Swain, Nick Cassavetes, Harve Presnell, Colm Feore, CCH Pounder, and Thomas Jane in supporting roles.
Principal photography began on January 4, 1997 in
Los Angeles and wrapped on April 1.
The film score was composed by John Powell.
It was the first Hollywood film in which Woo was given major creative control.
Face/Off was theatrically released on June 27, 1997 in the United States by Paramount Pictures and
internationally by Buena Vista International through its Touchstone Pictures banner.
It earned critical acclaim for the performances by Cage and
Travolta and its stylized action sequences.
Face/Off earned $245.7 million worldwide on a $80 million budget,
making it the 11th highest-grossing film of 1997.
At the 70th Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best Sound Effects Editing.
Over the years since its release, Face/Off has gained a cult
following and is considered as one of Woo's best films.
The film explores themes of prison, biological
weapon, prisoner, bomb, undercover.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.